Listen!
After all, if the stars are lit —
Does that mean — somebody needs them?
Does that mean — somebody wants them to be?
Does that mean — somebody calls these little specks of spit
A pearl?
And, straining himself to breaking,
In blizzards of midday dust,
He bursts in on God,
Afraid he’s come too late,
Weeps,
Kisses His sinewy hand,
Begs —
That there must be a star! —
Swears —
He won’t survive this starless torment!
And afterward
He goes about anxious,
But calm on the outside.
He says to someone:
“You’re all right now, aren’t you?
Not afraid?
Yes?!”
Listen!
After all, if the stars
Are lit —
Does that mean — somebody needs them?
Does that mean — it is essential
That every evening
Above the rooftops
At least one star should light up?!